Guide to the Ida Merriam papers, 1926-1983 MS2086
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Administrative files, 1935-1983; MS2086 Series 1
  - Surplus Food Allotment Bill Proposal, 1955-1981 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Task Force on Income Maintenance-Children, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Task Force on Income Maintenance-Cost of Estimates, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Task Force on Income Maintenance Disability Insurance, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Task Force on Income Maintenance-OASDI, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Task Force on Low Incomes, 1954-1963 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Task Force on Income Maintenance-Members, Minutes, Etc, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Task Force on Income Maintenance-1964 Poverty (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Task Force to Review Proposals for Maturing the OASI System, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Tax Treatment of Aged and Social Security Benefits, 1963-1973 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Taxation with Representation-Social Security Financing, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Title XVI-Medical Association, 1960 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Unemployment Compensation Financing/Financing Old-Age Reserve, 1938 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Unemployment Insurance Program-Dismissal Compensation, 1940-1943 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - UN-NGO, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - U.N. Social Services-Social Commission [1/2], 1965 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - U.N. Social Services-Social Commission [2/2], 1965 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - United Social Insurance System [1/2], 1939-1943 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - United Social Insurance System [2/2], 1939-1943 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - U.S. Department of Agriculture-Programs to Effectuate a Long-Range Policy of Abundance, 1947 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Uses of Poverty Index, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Veterans Administration Payments to Hospitals, 1960-1961 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Voluntary Health Insurance Coverage, etc, 1959-1960 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Welfare Reform, 1968-1972 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Wives (Women) Benefits, 1966 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Working Group on Adequacy, 1957-1959 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Memos on old age assistance and unemployment, 1935; Series 1 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Social Security pamphlets, 1935-1936; Series 1 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Social Security/Pensions, Undated; Series 1 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Background on Social Security [1/2], 1935-1970; Series 1 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Background on Social Security [2/2], 1970-1973; Series 1 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Background of Social Security, 1980-1983; Series 1 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Discussion of Social Security, 1975-1978; Series 1 (Box 58, Folder 2)
- Legislation, 1935-1972; MS2086 Series 2
  This series contains drafts of bills, bill proposals, memoranda, and notes. The material dates from 1935-1972. Topics include various heath insurance-related legislation such as the Wagner-Murray-Dingell Bill, drafted to create a national social insurance system. Other topics include Old-Age and Survivors Insurance (OASI) legislation, Social Security legislation amendments, and hospital insurance.
  - Administration OASI Bill, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Agency Committee, 1946-1947 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Anderson-Kennedy Bill, 1960 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Advisory Council, 1948 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Bills Introduced in 83rd Congress Committee on Intergovernmental Relations, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - California Health Insurance Bills, 1944-1945 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Catholic Voluntary Health Plan, 1949 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Commission on Intergovernmental Relations-Internal HEW Memoranda, 1951-1955 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Committee on Federal Aid to Welfare-Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1954-1955 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Comparison of 1943, 1945. Wagner-Murray-Dingell Bills and Social Security Act (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Curtis Subcommittee, 1953 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - DHEW Plans, 1959-1960 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Dept. 1954 Legislative Program-OASI (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Dept. 1954 Legislative Program-P.A. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Dept. 1954 Legislative Program-General (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Department Legislative Program, 1954-Health and Vocatinal Rehibilitation (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Eliot Bill and Comments, 1942 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Family Assistance Program [1/2], 1969 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Family Assistance Program [2/2], 1969 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Family Assistance Program, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Foreign Systems-Comparisons-Various Aspects pending Legislation, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Forand Bill, 1957-1958 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Forand Bill, 1959-1960 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Health Insurance for Aged-Bills and Proposals, 1960 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Health Bills, 1950-1951 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Health Bills, 1953-1954 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Health Bills-S. 1679, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Health Insurance Bills, Summaries, Etc, 1940-1952 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Health Insurance-S.5, 1949 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Health Insurance Debate-Spreads, articles, etc, 1943-1946 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Health Insurance-Presidential Messages, 1945-1950 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - H.R. 4222 Hearings Replies to Rep. Thomas B. Curtis and to Senator Carlson, 1961 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - H.R. 7199 Hearings, 1954 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - H.R. 3920 2. 880 Hospital Insurance, 1963 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - H.R. 4700, 1959-1960 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - H.R. 6000, 1949-1950 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Legislation and Legislative Planning, 1953 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Legislation-OASI, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Legislative History, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Ideas, 1968 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Legislative Planning, 1951 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Legislative Planning, 1952 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Major Legislative Proposals for Financing Personal Health Services for the Aged, 1939-1961 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - McNamara Health Bill, 1960 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - National Health Act, 1945 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - National Health Insurance Proposals-Provisions of Bills Introduced in the 93rd Congress as of October 1973, 1973 October (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - H.R. 7800-OASI Amendments, 1952 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - OASDI-H.R. 2893, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - OASDI Legislative Proposals, 1959 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Other Health Bills, 1949 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Public Assistance 1959-Legislative Proposals-Blanketing in (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - HRI-Poverty Reduction, 1968-1971 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Report to the President of the Committee on Economic Security, 1935 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - H.R. 12580-Senate Amendments-Cost Estimates, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - SSA Legislative Amendments-Sept. 1953 and Earlier Documents Relating Thereto [1/2], 1953 September (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - SSA Legislative Amendments-Sept. 1953 and Earlier Documents Relating Thereto [2/2], 1953 September (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Social Security Proposals, oustide groups, 1953-1954 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Social Security Legislation Throughout the World, 1949 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Social Security, Welfare Policy and Unemployment Disability Insurance, 1947-1948 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Taft Health Bills, 1946-1947 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Taxation of the Aged, 1961-1963 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - TDI Alternative Federal Policy Positions, 1947-1957 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - S.1606 - Testimony, Drafts RE: Changes, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Unemployment Insurance Legislation, 1954 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Various Bills - Welfare, OASI, etc, 1949-1954 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Ways and Means Drafts, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - S.1620 - Wagner Health Bill, 1939 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - S.1161 Wagner - Murray - Dingell Bill, 1943 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - S.1050 Wagner - Murray - Dingell Bill, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Wagner - Murray - Dingell Bill S.1320, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - S.1606 Wagner - Murray - Dingel National Health Insurance Program, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Welfare Reform Research and Evaluation H.R.I and other, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 10)
- Reports and studies, 1934-1979; MS2086 Series 3
  The materials of this series include statistical reports papers, and general reference materials related to the Social Security Administration. The material dates from 1934-1979. Topics include the United Nations Report on the World Social Situation, Social Security Bulletins with statistical supplements, and economic and welfare studies.
  - Abstract of Unemployment Insurance Legislation in European Countries Volume 11, 1938 May (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - The Administration of Automatic Merit Rsting Under Pooled-Fund Laws, 1938 September (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Agency Research (ICM-Collins Report), 1947 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Agency Research Survey, 1948 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Analyzing the Use of Staff Time in Public Assistance Agencies, 1941 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Appendix to Tables I to XXV - Earnings and Social Security in the United States, 1943 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Articles on Women and Social Security, 1972-1975 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Some Aspects of the American Social Insurance Program - A symposium, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Background Facts on Health Care and Economic Situation of the Aged, 1961 April (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Basic Cost Calculations Relating to Proposals to Provide Hospitalization and other Medical Care Services to OASDI Beneficiaries, 1958 January 20 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Some Basic Readings in Social Security, 1947 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Some Basic Readings in Social Security 1950 Supplement (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Basic Readings in Social Security (Social Welfare/Insurance), 1956 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 41)
  - Basic Readings in Social Security, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Basic Readings in Social Security, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Building America's Health - A Report to the President - America's Health Status, Needs and Resources Volume 2, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Building America's Health - A Report to the President - America's Health Status, Needs and Resources Volume 3, A Statistical Appendix, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Building America's Health - A Report to the President - Financing A Health Program for America Volume 4, 1951 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Building America's Health - Message from the President of the United States - Findings and Recommendations Volume 1, 1953 January 09 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Bureau of Labor Statistics Fourth Annual Conference with Research Directors of National and International Unions in Co-operation with Social Security Board Part 1, 1943 June 23-24 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Cash Benefits Under the New Zealand Social Security Program, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Cash Benefits Under Voluntary Disability Insurance in the U.S, 1941 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Changes in Female Labor Force Experience 1961-71, and the Effect on Earnings, 1961-1971 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 42)
  - Changes in Income Situations of Different Age Groups, 1964 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Continuation to 1952 of Historical Statistics of the United States, 1789-1945 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Cost of Living Per Aged Persons, 1943 October (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - CRA - Original Report, 1956-1957 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - CWHS User's Conference (Wage Statistics), 1970 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Data Processing in the Social Security Administration, 1967 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Directory of Health Insurance Plans other than Blue Cross or Blue Shield Plans or Insurance Companies, 1970 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Divorce Study, 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Double Decker Working Group Report, 1953 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Economic Assumptions Underlying the Medium Range Projections of the Federal Old Age and Survivors Insurance and Disability Trust Funds, 1966-1975 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Economic Perspectives 1943-1948 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 43)
  - Economic Security for Americans - The Americans Assembly, 1953 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Social Status of the Negro in the United States, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Economic Status of the Aged, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Effect of a Shortened Waiting Period on Unemployment Benefit Costs, 1938 December (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Elements of a Variable Grant Formula, 1938 December (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Employee Benefit Plans in the Electric and Gas Utility Industries, 1952 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Estimates of Covered Labor Force, Converted Employment, Taxable Wage, and Taxes Colelctible Social Security Act, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Evaluation and Measurement System - Exhibits - Executive Staff Presentation, 1969 March (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Family Studies, 1958 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Federal Revenue and Expenditures in the Several States - Averages for the Fiscal Years 1959-1961 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Federal Taxes and the Measurement of State Capacity, 1954 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Fifty Employee Benefit Plans in the Basic Steel Industry, 1947 November (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Financing Care of the Mentally Ill Under Medicare and Mediaid. U.S Department of Health, Education and Welfare - SSA Office of Research and Statistics, 1970 October (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Financing Health Care for the Aged, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 44)
  - The Fiscal Capacity of the States - A source Book [1/2], 1937 September (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The Fiscal Capacity of the States - A source Book [2/2], 1937 September (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - The Fiscal Capacity of the States - A source Book [1/2], 1938 April (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - The Fiscal Capacity of the States - A source Book [2/2], 1938 April (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Fluctuation in Employment Covered by the Federal Old Age Insurance Program, 1939 August (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - General Relief Operations of Public Agencies in Selected Large Cities, 1938 January-1939 June (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - The Health Care of the Aged - Background Facts Relating to the Financing Problem, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Historical Statistics of the United States - Continuation to 1962 and Revisions, 1965 (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Hospitalization and Insurance Among Aged Persons - A Study Based on a Census Survey, 1952 March (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - ILO Report to the Government of Thailand on the Application of the Social Insurance Act, Geneva, 1956 (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 45)
  - Illustrative Estimates of Federal Expenditures and Revenues, By States, 1956 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - The Impact of Medicare, 1969 (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Independant Plans Providing Medical Care and the Hospitalization Insurance in 1949 in the United States - 1950 Surveys, 1952 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Independant Plans Providing Medical Care and Hospitalization Insurance in 1949 in the United States - 1950 Survey (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - An Integrated System of Demographic, manpower and Social Statistics and its Link with the System of National Economic Accounts, 1970 May 28 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - International Survey of Programmes of Social Development, 1955 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - ISSA Poverty Studies, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - ISSA Report on the Continuation of the Study on the relationship between Family Allowances Schemes and Social Services, Geneva, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Industrial Classification and Employmer Account numbers in State Unemployment Compensation Agenices, 1938 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Joint Economic Committee Low Income Study, 1949 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 46)
  - Labour Force Reserves, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Marjorie Shearon - Economic Status of the Aged, 1941-1942 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - The Matching Requirements in Federal Agent Legislation in relation to Variation in State Fiscal Capacity, 1942 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Measuring Income Security of the Aged - A Source Book, 1959 June (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Measurement of Variations in State Economic and Fiscal Capacity, 1943 March (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Medical Care Costs and Prices: Background Book, 1972 January (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Medical and Hospital Services provided under Prepayment Arrangement - Trinity Hospital, Little Rock, Arkansas, 1941-1942 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Medical Care and Costs in Relation to Family Income - A Statistical Source Book, 1943 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - The Methodology of National Social Service Surveys - Report of the Export Group - Unkel, Federal Republic of Germany, 1964 June 07-13 (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - National Committee on Unemployment Compensation, 1964-1980 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - National Health Conference, July 18-19-20, 1938 called by Interdepartmental Committee to co-ordinate Health and Welfare Activities, 1938 June 18-20 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 47)
  - The Nation's Health - A report to the President, 1948 September (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Need for Medical Care Insurance, 1944 April (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Need for Medical Care Insurance, 1944 April (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - The Need for a National Health Program - Report of the Technical Committee on Medical Care, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - New York State Committee on Low Incomes, 1957-1958 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Nineteen Employee Benefit Plans in the Airframe Industry, 1951 January (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Nineteen Employee Benefit Plans in the Airframe Industry, 1951 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - The Non Cash Need of Aged Persons Affecting their Individual and Social Security - An Annotated Bibliography, 1948 March (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - The Objectives of the Social Security Administration, 1965 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Old Age in Sweden - A Program of Social Security, 1940 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - The Organization of Medical Care under Social Security, Geneva, 1969 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Outline of Federal Retirement Systems, 1948 June (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 48)
  - Part 2 - Report of the Study Committee on Federal Aid to Welfare to the Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1955 January (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Permanent and Total Diability Benefit Provisions in Industrial Retirement Plans, 1950 June (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - A plan for a case census of Recipients of Public Assistance, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Poverty Estimates, 1964-1969 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Povery Studies - other countries, 1963-1964 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Report on the World Social Situation, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Preliminary Report of the Study Committee on the Federal Aid to Welfare to the Commission of Intergovernmental Relations, 1954 November (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - The Prevalence of Disability in the United States with Special Reference to Disability Insurance, 1941 January (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - The Principle of equalization applied to the allocation of grants in Aid, 1947 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Principle Underlying Disqualification for Benefits in Unemployment Compensation Part 1: Refusal of Suitable Employment, 1938 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Principles of a Nation-Wide Health Program - Report of the Health Program Conference, 1944 November (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Private Health Insurance Part 1: Changing Patterns of Medical Care Demand and Supply in Relation to Health Insurance, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Private Health Insurance Part 2: Problems, Pressures and Prospects, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Private Health Insurance Part 2: Problems, Pressures and Prospects, 1958 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Private Health Insurance and Medical Care Conference Paper, 1968 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 49)
  - Proposed Amendment to Social Security Act with Respect to Medical Services for Recipients of Public Assistance Copy 1, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Quantitiative Analysis of Unemployment Compensation Simplification Proposal, 1938 October (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Reimbursement Incentives for Medical Care-Objectives and Alternatives, 1968 March (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Report of Ad Hoc Committee on Public Welfare to the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1961 September (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Report of the Committee on Economic Security to the President - Final Report on Risks to Economic Security Arising out of Illness, undated (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Report on Faculty Seminar on Income Maintanance - Univ. of Michigan, 1957 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Reprot on Hospitalization Insurance for OASDI Aged Beneficiaries - Comments and drafts, outside, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Report of the Second Planning Conference on the European Social Welfare Programme Geneva 17-19, 1964 February (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Hew Task Force on the Treatment of Women Under Social Security, 1978 February (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Report of the Task Force on Welfare [1/3], 1961 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 50)
  - Report of the Task Force on Welfare [2/3], 1961 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Report of the Task Force on Welfare [3/3], 1961 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Report of the Study Committee on Federal Aid to Welfare to the Commission on Intergovernmental Relations, 1955 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Retirement Benefits based on a Married Couple's Combined Earnings, 1978 July 12 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - On the Revision of Historical Statistics of the United States,1789-1945, 1952 April (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Scope if protection under state and Local Government Retirement Systems, 1944 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Seasonal Workers and Unemployment Insurance in Great Britan, German, and Austria, 1940 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Seasonal Employment in Ohio Canning Oil Preserving Establishments 1926-1936, 1938 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 51)
  - Seventy Three Emplyee Benefit Plans in the Petroleum Refining Industry, 1951 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Shearon, 1947-1950 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Social Data on Recipients of Public Assistance Accepted in 1937-1938 Port 3 - Aid to the Blind: Tables (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1946 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1948 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1943 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1944 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Social Security Yearbook, 1942 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Sources if Statistics on Benefits and Beneficiaries under Workmen's Compensation Program, 1942 March (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 52)
  - Social Data on Recipients of Public Assistance Accepted in 1938-1939 Part 1 - Old-Age assistance: tables (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Social Insurance Changes, 1949-1950 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Social Insurance Financing in Relation to Consumer Income and Expenditures, 1946 June (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Social Indicators, 1973-1976 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Social Securities Anniversary - 1968 (A third of a century) (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Social Security Board Bureau of Researc and Statistics - Merit Rating and Unemployment Compensation, 1937 October (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Social Security Board Bureau of Research and Statistics Bureau Memorandum No. 31 - Seasonal Workers and Unemployment Compensation, 1938 July (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Social Security Bulletin - Annual Statistical Supplement, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Social Security Bulletin - Annual Statistical Supplement, 1954 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Social Security Bulletin - Annual Statistical Supplement, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Social Security Bulletin - Annual Statistical Supplement, 1957 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Social Security Bulletin - Annual Statistical Supplement, 1958 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Social Security Bulletin - Annual Statistical Supplement, 1959 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Social Security and the changing Roles of Men and Women, 1979 February (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Social Security Financing, 1952 (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Reports and studies, undated (Box 53)
  - Social Security Programs in the United States, 1964 September (Box 53, Folder 1)